# **Craig Parry**

linkedin.com/in/craig-parry-599a70144/

Location: Santa Fe, NM, USA Email: craigparry1992@gmail.com | Mobile: 505-660-3719

#### SOFTWARE ENGINEER

I am a software engineer with experience in Computer Science, Web Development, and Software Development. I have knowledge of popular frameworks such as **React with Vite**, **Next.JS**, **Django**, **FastApi** and experience with **REST APIs**, **MVC frameworks**, **OOP**, and **DevOps practices**.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### **United Healthcare/Optum**

Software Engineer

May 2022 – Present Remote – Santa Fe, NM

- Enterprise Status displays monitoring alerts and current application up/down status for critical applications. I gathered requirements, investigated currently deployed application monitoring of vital business functions, and integrated monitoring alerts into the Enterprise Status page. I deployed cloud infrastructure and developed back-end data extraction pipelines for the web application.
- Lead summer intern team 2023 in an agile development environment for proof of concept utilizing React, Django, PostgreSQL, and docker.
- Migration of existing Django/React/Postgres application hosted on RHEL to an in-house Kubernetes cloud deployment
- Worked in small teams developing web applications as well as independently maintained and developed new features for production applications
- Created, modified and tested api endpoints in Django and FastApi. Implemented CRUD operations interacting with postgres, MongoDB, and neo4J databases
- Secured web apps with internal LDAP server and implemented JWT(JSON Web tokens) for authorization. Cleaned code smells and resolved dependency CVE's.
- Implemented full-stack features starting from feature ideation and requirements extraction with the product owner.
- · Bug fixes, server and deployment troubleshooting, certificate rotation, and dockerization
- Migrated Github Enterprise Server Repository to Enterprise Cloud and converted Jenkins pipelines to GithubActions workflow
- Deployed applications with docker swarm and Kubernetes

Terry Crowder: crowder@optum.com

## **OpenEye Scientific Software**

Infrastructure Engineer-Automated Testing intern

May 2020 – Aug 2020 Santa Fe, NM

• Worked independently and remotely during Covid Protocols on an automation project streamlining Amazon trusted advisor alerts and creating relevant tickets as Jira Issues for tracking. This project helped the DevOps team identify security issues.

Alex Hamilton: ahamilton@eyesopen.com

#### **UNM CS Department**

Peer Grader/Tutor

Aug 2019 – Dec 2020 Albuquerque, NM

- Prepared lab lectures for C programming and data structures, graded and tutored students on assignments and test preparation.
- Learned time management and how to communicate my working knowledge of Java to introductory-level students.

Soraya Abad-Mota: soraya@cs.unm.edu

# **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Languages : JavaScript, TypeScript, Python, Java, HTML, CSS, C, Haskell, Prolog

Frameworks : React.js, Vite, Django, FastApi, Pandas, PyMongo

Databases : MongoDB, PostgreSQL, Neo4JDev Tools : Visual Studio Code, Github

**DevOps** : Docker, Kubernetes, Jenkins, GitHub Actions, SonarQube

## **EDUCATION**

#### **University of New Mexico**

Master of Science in Computer Science - 3.84

#### **University of New Mexico**

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science - 3.87

#### **University of New Mexico**

Bachelor of Arts in Psychology - 3.81

Albuquerque, NM Aug 2021 – May 2022

Albuquerque, NM Jan 2018 – May 2021

Albuquerque, NM Aug 2012 – May 2016

## **EDUCATIONAL PROJECTS**

### github.com/craigparry

## **Compiler (Compiler Design)**

Haskell, Risc-V, C

- Project goal- Implement a multi-stage compiler using lexing and parsing tools. Implementing the theoretical While language and generating code in RISC-V assembly. Using an intermediate representation perform code optimizations.
- Outcome- Working in a team of 4 we implemented a working compiler in Haskell. Understanding of finite automata, context free grammar, abstract syntax trees, RISC-V assembly, parsing theory and optimization techniques for compilers (dead code elimination, constant folding, register allocation).

# **Semantic Web (Databases)**

JSON-LD, Python

- Project goal- Create a mapping from Linked.art and Schema.org schemas and implement the mapping using JSON-LD semantic web annotation structures.
- Outcome- Created project proposal, design documentation, diagrams, and a python script mapping the two schemas in coordination with my group project partner.

# Vampires and Werewolves/Sliding Tile (Artificial Intelligence)

Prolog

- Project Goal- to solve classic state space search problems using Prolog. Create the definition of the state space, legal moves, and rules required and design a heuristic to use A\*, depth-first search, and breadth-first search functions to solve the problems.
- Outcome- An effective design of state space, rules, and heuristic using Prolog. Clocking of solver different state spaces designed to test the limits of A\* compared to traditional searches.

## **Scrabble (Design of Large Programs)**

Java, JavaFx

- Project Goal: Create a word solver that can read the current state of the scrabble board, find the best possible solution to maximizing the player's move score, and check for move correctness. Implementing an interactive graphical user interface (GUI) to accompany the solver.
- Outcome: A solver effective at producing correct results for a majority of test cases and a GUI with minimal bugs. I learned how to organize and manage the production of large programs.